我的名字是詹姆斯·提比留斯·柯克
My name is Captain James Tiberius Kirk
星际联邦的舰长
of the United Federation of Planets.
我谨以弗比安共和国的中立代表身份
I am appearing before you as a neutral representative
前来面见诸位
of the Fibonan Republic.
我带来了友好信息
I bring you a message of goodwill
同时呈交尊贵的提纳克希议员团
and present to you esteemed members of the Teenaxi Delegation,
一份来自弗比安最高议会的礼物
a gift from the Fibonan High Council
并致以最高敬意
with the highest regard.
它哪里坏了
What's wrong with it?
你说什么
Uh, excuse me?
他们干嘛不想再要了
Why don't they want it anymore?
呃 就是 这其实是一件古代的武器
Uh, well, this was once a piece of an ancient weapon,
现在他们把它当做象征 表
and now they offer it as a symbol of...
表示和平
Of peace.
在弗比安的文化里
In the Fibonan culture,
交出武器就意味着 提议停战
to surrender a weapon is an offer of truce.
他们怎么得到的
How did they come by it?
他们告诉我 他们很久以前就得到了
They told me they acquired it a long time ago.
那就是偷来的
So they stole it, then.
不是 他们 好吧 我也不清楚
No, they, um... Well, I don't know.
你们不了解弗比安人 远不如我们
You don't know the Fibonans like we do!
是啊 你说的非常对 尊敬的阁下 这份礼物
Yeah, that's very true. Your Excellency, this gift...
他们就是一群不值得信赖的窃贼
They're a crowd of untrustworthy thieves
就想看到我们被砍死在自己的床上
who want to see us murdered in our own beds!
这件深受钟爱的礼物 它象征着信任与和平
This beloved artifact is a symbol of trust and peace.
他们想把我们切成肉排 然后再放在火上烤
They want to chop us into pieces and roast us over a fire!
不 他们 我觉得不会那样
No, no... I don't think that's true.
再吃掉我们
And eat us!
什么
What?
斯科蒂 快把我弄回去
Scotty! Get me out of here!
- 快啊 - 斯科蒂
- That was quick. - Scotty!
地面上的干扰非常严重 长官
There's quite a bit of surface interference, sir.
斯科蒂
Scotty!
快把它弄下来
Get it off of me!
又把我的制服撕破了
I ripped my shirt again.
怎么样
How'd it go?
舰长 您和提纳克希人达成和平协议了吗
Captain, did you manage to broker a treaty with the Teenaxi?
噢 这么说吧 快谈到了
Uh... Let's just say I came up short.
你能 嗯 这个日志 把它锁资料库里
Will you, uh, log that and put it in the vault,
斯波克 谢谢
Spock? Thank you.
吉姆 你看起来很狼狈
Jim, you look like crap.
谢了 老骨头
Thank you, Bones.
你太阳穴上的那个小血管又爆出来了 没事吧
You got that little vein popping out of your temple again. You okay?
从没这么好过 又是舰队里的一天罢了
Never better! Just another day in the fleet.
舰长日志 星历2263.2
Captain's Log, Stardate 2263.2.
今天是我们进入深太空的第966天
Today is our 966th day in deep space,
我们的五年任务也快到了第三年
a little under three years into our five-year mission.
在深空待的时间越长
The more time we spend out here,
就越来越难以分辨 今天何时结束
the harder it is to tell where one day ends
下一天何时开始
and the next one begins.
连脚踏实地的感觉也变成了挑战
It can be a challenge to feel grounded
因为重力也是人工制造的
when even gravity is artificial.
不过我们还是尽己所能 让它感觉像个家
But, well, we do what we can to make it feel like home.
不论延长的外太空逗留时间如何艰苦
The crew, as always, continues to act admirably
还是 要让他们必须做出的个人牺牲
despite the rigors of our extended stay here in outer space.
船员们都一如既往地延续着十分出色的表现
And the personal sacrifices they have made.
我们从未间断寻找新的生命形式
We continue to search for new life forms
是为了建立起牢固的外交关系
in order to establish firm diplomatic ties.
在星图未标绘的地域延长逗留时间
Our extended time in uncharted territory
考验着飞船的机械性能
has stretched the ship's mechanical capacities.
但幸运的是 我们的轮机工程部
But fortunately our engineering department,
在斯科蒂先生的率领下 完全能胜任工作
led by Mr. Scott, is more than up to the job.
除了星舰 旷日持久的共居生活
The ship aside, prolonged cohabitation has
也已经对人际动力学产生了确实的影响
definitely had effects on interpersonal dynamics.
有一些向好的方向发展
Some experiences for the better,
而另一些就越来越糟
and some for the worse.
至于我 开始觉得情况
As for me, things have started to
有一点儿 难以捉摸
feel a little episodic.
我们走得越远 我就越发觉自己会去想
The farther out we go, the more I find myself wondering
我们究竟想努力达成什么
what it is we're trying to accomplish.
如果宇宙真的无边无际
If the universe is truly endless,
那么 我们难道不是在谋求永远无法企及的事吗
then are we not striving for something forever out of reach?
进取号将按照预定日程
The Enterprise is scheduled
到约克城基地进行补给
for a reprovisioning stop at Yorktown,
那是联邦最新也是最先进的星舰基地
the Federation's newest and most advanced starbase.
也许离开日常工作 会提供一时喘息之机
Perhaps a break from routine will offer up some respite
暂别神秘的未知
from the mysteries of the unknown.
上传至联邦档案资料库  源星球:未知
来源方:弗比安共和国
拒收方:提纳克希议员团
抱歉 来晚了
Sorry I'm late.
金瑟咳出了高浓度绿色黏性物质
Keenser's leaking some kind of highly acidic green goo,
斯科蒂就怕他对着曲速核咳嗽
and Scotty's terrified he's gonna sneeze on the warp core
那会要了我们的命
and kill us all.
你在喝什么什么玩意儿
What the hell are you drinking?
就是在瑟塞斯弄来的那瓶蜥蜴人的白兰地
Uh, I'm pretty sure it's the rest of that Saurian brandy we picked up on Thasus.
天呐 老弟 你是想把自己喝瞎吗
My God, man, are you trying to go blind?
那东西是违法的
That stuff's illegal.
何况 我在契科夫的柜子里发现了这个
Besides, I found this in Chekov's locker.
- 喔 - 对吧
- Wow. - Right?
我一直觉得他该是个
I mean, I always assumed he'd be
- 喝伏特加的好手 - 喝伏特加的好手 一点儿没错
- a vodka man. - A vodka guy, exactly.
我想给你的生日弄点像样的东西
I wanted to have something appropriate for your birthday.
你还有几天 你知道我不太在乎这事儿
Uh, that's in a couple days. You know I don't care about that.
我知道 我知道你不太想庆祝生日
I know. I know you don't like celebrating it on the day
是因为那天你老爸化作了星尘
because it's also the day your pa bit the dust.
我的神经还算敏感
I was being sensitive.
他们教过你怎么对待别人吗 在医学院
Did they teach you about bedside manner in medical school?
敬你那大脑的魅力
It's just your southern charm.
- 噢 是啊 真不错 - 噢
- Oh, yeah. That's good. - Ooh.
好酒
Lordy!
给你妈妈打个电话
Are you gonna call your mom?
是啊 当然会了 那天再打给她
Yeah, of course. I'll call her on the day.
我又老了一岁
I'm one year older.
是啊 生日就这个意思
Yep, that's usually how it works.
他永远也到不了我这个年纪了
A year older than he ever got to be.
他加入星际舰队 是因为
He joined Starfleet because he...
他有信仰
He believed in it.
而我是为了一个赌
I joined on a dare.
你加入是想让自己不要辜负他
You joined to see if you could live up to him.
是啊 那么久以来 你一直想成为乔治·柯克
Uh, you spent all this time trying to be George Kirk
可现在你却在想吉姆该是什么样
and now you're wondering just what it means to be Jim.
你为什么会在这里
Why you're out here.
耳聪目明 那一脑袋的头发
To perfect eyesight and a full head of hair.
我是柯克
Kirk here.
舰长 即将抵达约克城基地
Captain, approaching Yorktown base.
我马上过去 苏鲁先生
I'm on my way, Mr. Sulu.
生日的事儿先别说出去
Let's keep this birthday thing under wraps, huh?
你知道我的 敏感先生嘛
Yeah, you know me. Mr. Sensitive.
哇 真是太壮观了
Wow. That is impressive.
是啊 她是个美人儿 是不是
Aye, she's a beauty, isn't she?
真是个畸形的庞然大物
What a damn monstrosity!
就不能找个星球借点儿地方
Couldn't we just rent some space on a planet?
阐明地理上的偏好
Showing geographical favoritism
会在正式加入联邦世界中
among inducted Federation worlds
引发外交紧张
could cause diplomatic tension.
看着它就让人紧张
Oh, you don't think that looks tense?
像个在太空里要爆掉的该死的雪花球
Looks like a damn snow globe in space just waiting to break!
就你会这么说 老骨头
Oh, that's the spirit, Bones.
斯波克
Spock!
现在有时间吗
Do you have a moment?
当然有 妮欧塔
Of course, Nyota.
我想你应该把它拿回去
I think you should have this back.
毕竟 它属于你母亲
After all, it belonged to your mother.
这并不符合瓦肯习俗
It's not in the Vulcan custom
重新接受已被送做礼物的东西
to receive again that which was given as a gift.
你俩分手了
You guys break up?
你干了什么
What'd you do?
一个典型的抽象提问 医生
A typically reductive inquiry, Doctor.
要知道 斯波克
You know, Spock,
如果地球的姑娘说 问题在我不在你
if an Earth girl says, uh, "It's me, not you,"
那你肯定有问题
it's definitely you.
打扰一下 斯波克中校
Excuse me. Commander Spock?
可以借用你一些时间吗
May we have a moment of your time?
这真是太棒了 你知道我还没来过这里吗
This is wonderful! You know I've never been here?
我觉得这里的酒吧全都一级棒
What I hear is that the bars here are excellent.
你们来了 我很高兴
I'm so glad you guys could come.
谢谢你们告知我这个消息
Thank you for bringing this to my attention.
生生不息 繁荣昌盛
Live long and prosper.
生于2230年6月  卒于2263年2月
斯波克大使
敌我级别警告 有飞船接近
IFF alert on incoming vessel.
非星联飞船
Unidentified. Non-Federation.
注意 不明身份飞船 你无授权接近
Attention, unidentified vessel. You are not authorized for approach.
关闭动力 等待指示
Power down and await instructions.
不明身份飞船 请服从指令
Unidentified vessel, please comply.
请用规范语言
Speak normally.
语言分析已经完成
Language analysis complete.
这个有用吗
Is this working?
通用翻译
这个有用吗
Is this working?
通用翻译
.
我们在星云内部执行科学任务
We were on a science mission inside the nebula.
我们的飞船受到 发生了很严重的故障
Our ship suffered a critical malfunction.
我乘逃生舱出来
I took an escape pod
然后 飞船就坠毁在了临近的星球上
before the ship crash landed on a nearby planet.
我们需要一艘飞船 能够在星云内部航行
We need a ship capable of navigating the nebula.
你们必须找
You must have someone
能帮助我们的人
who can help us.
我们追踪到了受困飞船
We tracked her stranded ship
在一处尚未标绘的星云里
to a sector of uncharted nebula,
在210 标号14
here at 2-1-0 mark 14.
- 远程扫描呢 - 没有数据
- Uh, long-range scan? - No data.
星云过于稠密 那是未知的空域
The nebula is too dense. It's uncharted space.
进取号的确配备有星际舰队最好的导航系统
Well, the Enterprise does have the best navigational system in the fleet.
她能应付
She could handle it.
这里唯一一艘运用更先进技术的星舰
The only ship here with more advanced technology
还在建造当中
is still under construction.
但我派出去的 不只是星舰
But it's not just the ship that I'm sending.
- 我这就集结船员- 舰长
- I'll gather the crew. - Captain.
星际舰队指挥部
Starfleet command sent me your application
把你晋升中将的批复发给了我 你想在这里就职吗
for the Vice Admiral position here at this installation.
是的 长官
Yes, ma'am. Um...
如果可以 我
If I may, I would
更愿意推荐斯波克中校
recommend Commander Spock replace me
接替我担任进取号舰长
as Captain of the Enterprise.
他是星际舰队军官的楷模 也会是位好舰长
He is an exemplary Starfleet officer. He'd make a great captain.
这并非不寻常 你知道
It isn't uncommon, you know,
就算是想要离任的舰长
even for a captain, to want to leave.
在广袤无垠的太空里 不会有相对方向
There is no relative direction in the vastness of space.
那只有你自己
There is only yourself,
你的飞船 你的船员
your ship, your crew.
只会比你想的更容易迷失航向
It's easier than you think, to get lost.
- 不是因为 - 申请我会递交总理事会
- It's not about... - I'll bring it up with the General Council.
你回来后再做讨论
We'll discuss it when you return.
是 长官
Ma'am.
- 斯波克先生 - 舰长
- Mr. Spock. - Captain.
- 你现在 - 我在想
- I was thinking... - Perhaps there...
- 不 你先说 - 舰长 你先说
- No, please. - Captain, after you.
我坚持
I insist.
等执行完任务 我们 应该坐下来
After this mission, we should, uh, sit down.
我有些事情要跟你说
There's something I need to talk to you about.
我也有事要跟你分享
I as well have something to share.
我们是好伙伴 对吗
We make a good team. Right?
我想我们是的
I believe we do.
这次我坚持
I insist.
乌胡拉上尉 打开全舰广播
Lieutenant Uhura, open a ship-wide channel.
是 舰长
Yes, Captain.
进取号全体船员请注意
Attention, crew of the Enterprise.
我们这次任务很明确
Our mission is straightforward.
前往营救困在一处未标绘空域行星上的船员
Rescue a crew stranded on a planet in uncharted space.
航行轨迹将穿过一片不稳定的星云
Our trajectory will take us through an unstable nebula,
期间会失去与星际舰队的一切通讯联络
one which will disable all communications with Starfleet.
就只能靠自己了
We're gonna be on our own.
而进取号有舰队其它星舰没有的
The Enterprise has something no other ship in the fleet has,
就是各位
you.
也希望大家能明白
And as we've come to understand,
没有什么是未知的
there is no such thing as the unknown,
我们只是暂时藏起来
only the temporarily hidden.
通话完毕
Kirk out.
读数显示 云层的密度在减少 长官
Mmm. Readings indicate cloud density diminishing, sir.
这里是奥泰梅德 我的飞船就困在这里
This is Altamid. My ship is stranded here.
正在接近奥泰梅德
Approaching Altamid.
M级行星
Class-M planet.
有大量地下进化活动
Massive subterranean development.
但地表无生命形态
But limited to no life forms on the surface.
接近警报 长官
Proximity alert, sir!
有一艘不明飞船正朝我们过来
We have an unknown ship heading right for us.
- 乌胡拉中尉 呼叫他们 - 好的 舰长
- Lieutenant Uhura, hail them. - Yes, Captain.
没有回应 我监测到了某种信号
No response. I am picking up some kind of signal.
联系 失败
联系 未知
他们干扰我们的信号
They're jamming us.
把它放大 苏鲁先生
Magnify, Mr. Sulu.
联系
[未知]
这是什么
What is this?
升起护盾 红色警戒
Shields up! Red alert!
全舰自由攻击
Fire at will.
长官 我们的相位炮只起到了很小的作用
Sir, our phasers are having minimal effect
鱼雷也没法跟踪它们的移动
and our torpedos can't track their movements!
所有武器全面开火
Fire everything we've got.
舰长 我们的武器无法匹配这样的交战
Captain, we are not equipped for this manner of engagement.
护盾屏蔽已经失效 长官
Shield frequencies have no effect, sir!
主屏障已损毁 护盾无法操控了
They took out the dish! Shields are inoperable!
- 进曲速 快走 苏鲁先生 - 是 长官
- Warp us out of here, Mr. Sulu. - Yes, sir.
我们怎么动都没动
Why the hell aren't we moving?
没法启动曲速驱动器 长官
I can't engage the warp drive, sir!
斯科蒂 我要曲速 马上
Scotty, I need warp now!
没法子 长官 曲速舱 它们
I cannae, sir! The nacelles, they've...
全没了
They've gone!
安全人员 启用所有应急规程
Security, engage all emergency procedures.
执行舰队安全协议28 准则代码1A0
Active protocol 28 Code One Alpha Zero.
所有人员进入警戒岗位
All personnel to alert stations.
长官 舰体出现破裂 12至15层
Sir, I have hull breaches in levels 12 to 15,
6 9 31 21层都有 长官
6, 9, 31 and 21, sir.
舰长 我现在还能把存储的能量从曲速核
Captain! There's a chance I can reroute the energy reserves
接到脉冲引擎上
from the warp core to the impulse engines.
如果再回到星云里 就能甩掉它们
If we can get back into the nebula, maybe we could lose them.
尽管放手去做 斯科蒂
Do whatever you have to, Scotty.
小不点儿 我们走
Wee man! Let's go.
清理完毕，克劳。
匹配等离子导管 听我命令准备变更
Fit the plasma conduits and stand by to reroute on my mark!
艾布纳塞到手了。
占领这艘飞船。
- 舰长 - 说 斯波克
- Captain. - Go, Spock.
我确认了
I have identified the individual
那个带领攻击小组的人
who appears to be leading the attack party.
他侵袭了资料库
He infiltrated the archive vault
拿走了我们要送给提纳克希人的那件武器
and removed the artifact from our mission on Teenax.
和他保持安全距离
Hold your distance until...
斯波克
Spock!
你们俩跟我走 苏鲁 由你来指挥
You two, with me. Sulu, you have the conn.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
我的天呐
My God.
临界警报
这是
What the hell?
医生
Doctor?
医生 我们必须马上撤离
Doctor, we must evacuate now!
柯克
Captain
舰长
Kirk.
好 我们的脉冲引擎动力100%
Yes! We are at 100% impulse.
干得漂亮 斯科蒂先生
Great work, Mr. Scott!
最大脉冲速度 进入星云
Maximum impulse towards the nebula.
是
Aye.
克劳，飞船掉头返航了！
切断它的喉咙。
柯克呼叫舰桥
Kirk to Bridge.
我们正在失去惯性阻尼器
We are losing the inertial dampeners!
全舰系统全部开始失效了 舰长
Systems are failing ship-wide, Captain.
正在封闭应急隔板
Emergency bulkheads are sealing,
可结构完整度只有18% 而且还在下降 长官
but structural integrity is at 18% and falling, sir!
全员弃船 苏鲁先生
Abandon ship, Mr. Sulu.
鸣发警报
Sound the alarm.
全员弃船 所有人员请立即撤离
Abandon ship. All personnel.
我们必须给逃生舱创造机会
We need to give those pods a chance to escape.
你能把那些飞船引开吗
Can you lead those ships away?
脉冲引擎还在从曲速驱动器中接收能量
Impulse engines are still trying to draw power from the warp reserve.
在碟部彻底分离以前我们不能动
We cannot move until the saucer is separated.
交给我来
I'll handle it.
遵命 长官
Aye-aye, sir.
全员弃船 所有人员请立即撤离
Abandon ship. All personnel evacuate immediately.
你没事吧 快帮帮我 把他扶起来
You okay? Oh, my God. Get him up. Help him up.
扶好了
Got you.
你们必须全部上逃生舱 快 快走
We've got to get you guys to an escape pod. Go.
快走 希尔少尉
Go! Ensign Syl.
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
好的 长官
Yes, sir.
我的老天
My God.
斯波克 他们把船员抓走了
Spock, they're taking the crew!
全员弃船 所有人员请立即撤离
Abandon ship. All personnel evacuate immediately.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
碟部应该分离完毕了
The saucer should be free by now!
我知道 苏鲁先生 舰长应该已经到了
I know, Mr. Sulu. The Captain should be there!
全员弃船 所有人员请立即撤离
All personnel evacuate immediately.
碟形部分分离
确认
脉冲引擎正在从辅助动力发生器获取能量
Impulse engines drawing power from auxiliary generators.
舰长
Captain!
碟部上面还有多少船员
How many of the crew are still aboard the saucer?
没有了
None.
如果我没有看错读数
But if I'm reading this correctly,
入侵者把船员都抓走了
the intruders are taking them.
舰长 我们被星球的重力捕获了
Captain, we are caught in the planet's gravity.
没有办法 逃脱了
We cannot pull away.
上凯尔文联络艇
Get to your Kelvin Pods.
- 明白 长官 - 是 舰长
- Yes, sir. - Aye, Captain.
快 我们走
Come on, let's go!
快走
Let's go.
快
Come on.
契科夫
Chekov!
你知道 你知道我们会受到攻击
You knew. You knew we'd be attacked.
你不明白
You don't understand.
舰长 柯克舰长
Captain! Captain Kirk!
是的 我骗了你们
Yes. I lied.
我们的飞船也受到了攻击
Our ship was attacked.
契科夫 查看信号 联络生还者
Chekov, check the comms for survivors.
- 是 是 是 先生 - 那人是谁
- Aye, Captain. - Who is he?
他的名字叫克劳
His name is Krall.
他抓走了我的船员 你的船员也一样
He took my crew. Like he took yours.
他怎么会对进取号那么了解
How did he know so much about the Enterprise?
我只知道如果我这样做
All I know is that if I did this,
他就会放了我的人
he would set them free.
契科夫 你在扫描仪上发现什么没有
Chekov, are you picking anything up on those scanners?
没有 长官
Nothing, sir.
- 他们会不会 - 不 不会
- What if they... - No, no.
是被带走了
He was taking them.
我们必须找到碟部
We have to find that saucer.
就算是最小的扫描系统
Even minimal scanning systems
也比三路仪的搜索范围大得多
will have more range than a tricorder.
是 舰长 这是有可能的
Aye, Captain, it's possible.
舰长
Captain.
我也是为了保护我的船员
I was protecting my crew.
我们正在寻找舰长。
你的名字是什么
What is your name?
你怎么懂我们的语言
How do you know our language?
我还懂你们的人
I know your kind.
我是联邦星舰进取号的妮欧塔·乌胡拉上尉
I am Lieutenant Nyota Uhura of the U.S.S. Enterprise.
你已经做出了对联邦的侵略行为
And you have committed an act of war against the...
星际联邦
Federation!
星际联邦才是侵略行为
Federation is an act of war.
是你攻击了我们
You attacked us.
你的舰长
Your captain...
为什么你要牺牲自己去救他
Why did you sacrifice yourself for him?
他也会这么做
He would have done the same.
要是他安全地逃离飞船 就会来救我们
And if he made it off of that ship, he will come for us.
正中我的下怀 乌胡拉上尉
I am counting on it, Lieutenant Uhura.
真不敢相信
I can't believe it.
天呐 斯波克
My God, Spock.
天呐
God...
到这边坐下
Sit down over here.
好了 好了 坐下 慢点儿
Okay. Okay, sit. Easy.
好了
Okay.
你要 尽量放松 不会有事的
Now, just try and relax. You're gonna be okay.
你语气中的强迫乐观态度
The forced optimism in your voice suggests
表明你正在试图激发镇静的感知意识
that you are trying to elicit a sense of calm in order to...
那就不用马粪哄你了
I'll cut the horseshit.
医生 我并未看出马的排泄物
Doctor, I fail to see how excrement of any kind
与我们的当前状况有任何关联
bears relevance on our current situation.
你干什么
What the hell are you doing?
必须离开 医生
We must keep moving, Doctor.
斯波克 这玩意儿穿进了你的腹部
Spock, this thing's punctured your iliac region!
时间是决定性要素
Time is a critical factor.
这话我正想告诉你
That's exactly what I'm trying to tell you.
听着 要是不取出来 你就没命了
Look, if I can't take this out, you're gonna die.
懂了 即便能取出来但止不住血 你也没命了
Okay? If I take it out and can't stop the bleeding, you're gonna die.
任一选项 其结果均无从上诉
I can see no appeal in either option.
是啊 不管信不信 我有同感
Believe it or not, neither can I.
那么 如果我记得正确的话
So, if I remember correctly,
瓦肯人的心脏应该在 对应人类的肝脏部位
the Vulcans have their hearts where humans have their livers.
很正确 医生
That is correct, Doctor.
这就是你 为什么这么冷漠
That explains a thing or two.
知道吗 你真走运 再往左一英寸
You know, you're lucky. An inch to the left...
你就没命了
And you'd be dead already.
我就不明白了 斯波克
I just don't get it, Spock.
我说他们 干嘛攻击我们
I mean, what did they attack us for?
我是说 大动干戈
I mean, they do all this for some
就为了连那些小动物都不要的那些小玩意儿
doodad that the tiny critters didn't want?
轻视单纯无法理解的事物
It is unwise to trivialize
并不明智 医生
that which one simply does not understand, Doctor.
不妨谨慎地假设 它比小玩意儿更为重要
We can safely assume it is more important than a doodad.
你成功地羞辱了我两次 斯波克
I think you just managed to insult me twice, Spock.
好了
Okay.
好了 斯波克 我就剩一个问题
All right, Spock, I just got one question.
- 你最喜欢 什么颜色 - 我并未看出颜色与
- What's your favorite color? - I fail to see the relevance.
是啊 他们说出其不意就没那么疼了
Yeah. They say it hurts less if it's a surprise.
如果可以采取你所熟悉的用语
If I may adopt a parlance with which you are familiar,
我可以把你的理论确认为 马粪
I can confirm your theory to be horseshit.
得赶紧离开这儿
We got to get out of here.
走吧
Come on.
逗我玩呢 你啊
You're kidding me, aren't you?
你们好
Hello there.
我叫蒙哥马利·斯科特
My name is Montgomery Scott.
那么 你们是谁
And, uh, who might you be?
看着点儿 小子
Watch it, sonny.
我可有用得很 但得我愿意 懂吗
I'm pretty handy when I want to be, all right?
别再来了
Don't come back!
这下让他们见识了 小姑娘
We certainly showed them, eh, lassie?
那归星际舰队所有 不能想拿就拿
That's Starfleet property, okay. You cannae just take it.
不过 今天我挺大方的 你就留着吧
Uh, but I'm feeling generous today, so have at it.
那个 哪里找到的
Where you get that?
- 你会说我们的话 - 在我房子里学的
- Is that English? - I learn it from my house.
哪里找到的
Where you get that?
是我的星际舰队徽章
It's my Starfleet insignia.
这什么意思
What does it mean?
意思就是 我是星际舰队的一名官员
Means that I'm an officer of Starfleet.
这是轮机工程部
Uh, engineering division.
轮机工程部
Engineering?
对 说得对 我修东西
That's right. I fix things.
我知道什么是轮机工程部
I know what is engineering.
想消灭我飞船的混蛋 你们不是一伙的吧
You're not with those bastards that killed my ship, are you?
我就当不是了
I'll take that as a no.
他叫克劳 他和他的
He is Krall. Him and his
蜜蜂
bees.
他们搜索行星要找 致命武器
They search the stars for a death machine.
他们就是你在这里的原因
They're the reason why you here.
我们都在这里的原因
Why we are all here.
什么 那三个讨厌鬼也是
Even those three scunners?
他们从天上掉下来 就像我和你
They have fallen from the sky, like me and you.
你跟我走 现在
Come with me. Now!
等等 我说等一下 小姑娘
Wait, no... Hang on a minute, lassie.
我今天碰上的事儿真不少
I'm having a difficult day here.
我必须要找到我的船员
I've got to find my crewmates.
我会帮你找到你的船员
I will help you find your mates.
然后你就要帮助我
And then you will help me.
要怎么帮
With what?
你想让我修东西
You want me to fix something?
是的 你帮我 我就帮你
Yes. You help me, and I help you.
那好吧 既然都已经这样了
All right, well, things being as they are,
说不准会有个好待遇
I doubt I'll get a better offer today,
那就 带路吧
so, lead the way.
很好
Good.
我是婕拉
I am Jaylah.
你是蒙哥马利·斯科特
And you are Montgomery Scott.
是 你可以叫我斯科蒂
Aye, Scotty.
快走吧 蒙哥马利·斯科蒂
Come now, Montgomery Scotty.
好嘞 等等我
All right, hold up.
是进取号
The Enterprise.
它可能都没法把能量输送到舰桥了 舰长
She may not even have power to the Bridge, Captain.
她肯定还有其它的招数
She still has a few tricks up her sleeve.
我敢打赌
I'd bet on it.
麦考伊呼叫进取号 请回答
McCoy to Enterprise. Come in.
麦考伊呼叫进取号
McCoy to Enterprise.
嗨 你得走慢点儿 斯波克
Hey, take it easy there, Spock.
刚才那只是临时处置
That was just a temporary fix back there.
我明白 医生
I understand, Doctor.
有意思
Fascinating.
不吉利 黑暗 还有危险
Ominous. Dark. Dangerous.
我们进去
We're going in.
耐人寻味
Intriguing.
这些符号与在袭击中
These symbols are the same as those
被劫的武器上的符号一致
depicted on the artifact taken in the attack.
你觉得它来源于这儿
You think it came from here?
看来如此
It would seem so.
见鬼 斯波克
Damn it, Spock.
放松 放松
Easy. Easy.
快点儿
Hurry.
到了没有
Are we there yet?
不要再问了
Stop asking that.
对不起
Sorry.
跟着我走
This is the way. Come.
当心脚底下 你肯定不想踩到我的陷阱
And watch your steps. You do not want to set off my traps.
噢 可真聪明
Oh. That's clever.
这是什么地方
What is this place?
这是我的房子
This is my house.
你的房子
Your house?
稍等一下 这不是飞船吗
Hold on a minute. Is this a ship?
我帮你找到你的朋友 然后你帮我修好它
I help you find your friends and you help me fix it.
我就能永远离开这个星球了
So I can leave this planet forever.
你 等一下 这是你的飞船
Wait a minute. Is this your ship?
不 蒙哥马利·斯科蒂
No, Montgomery Scotty.
是你们的飞船
It's yours.
我的老天呐
Oh, my good Lord.
星际联邦 富兰克林号
星舰代码NX326
舰长 看起来还有能量
Captain, it looks like there is power.
好的 我们去舰桥再搜索船员
All right, let's get to the Bridge and find the crew.
控制台没有受损 舰长
The console is intact, Captain.
我重新布线 把能量接过来
I will try to reroute power to it.
快一点儿
Work fast.
一旦把这里弄亮 就会引来很多的敌人
Once we get this place lit up, we're gonna draw a lot of attention.
你觉得呢 能找到他们吗
What do you think, can you find them?
是 舰长
Aye, Captain.
我正在重新配置扫描器
I am reconfiguring scanners to modulate
调整到搜索船员的频率
for the crew's signals.
你跟我来 我还有东西没拿
You're with me. I left something behind.
金瑟确实够厉害的
That is one heck of a cold.
干得漂亮 金瑟
Nice job, Keenser.
好了 在下一次轮班之前我们大概有15分钟
All right, we got about 15 minutes until the next guard rotation. Come on.
快走 快来
Let's go. Come on.
快点儿
Come on.
这是麦哲伦探测器
This is the Magellan Probe.
联邦就是用它找到了穿过星云的航线
The Federation was using these to find a way through the nebula.
它有什么用
What's he using it for?
那边有什么
What do you see?
他在探测器之间架设了亚空间通讯链接
He's been piggybacking the subspace links between the probes.
我们能用它发求救信号吗
Can we use it to send a distress signal?
我来试试
I can try.
安全连接已建立
访问中
发出去了
It's sent.
他曾访问过约克城基地的数据库
He's accessed the Yorktown database.
什么
What?
还有星际舰队的数据文件 星舰的日志
He's got Starfleet data files, ship logs,
也包括进取号的
including the Enterprise.
原来他一直在监视我们
He's been watching us this whole time.
舰长
Captain,
那件武器始终都藏在星舰上吗
the artifact was on the ship the whole time?
带着它被抓 我承担不起那么大的责任
I couldn't afford to get caught with it,
所以就藏在这儿了
so I hid it in here.
告诉克劳 我拿到艾布纳塞了
Tell Krall I have the Abronath.
只要听到悲伤的故事 你都会相信
Do you believe every sad story you hear?
也不全是
Not every.
你把枪放下
Put the phaser down.
请吧
Please.
找到船员了吗 契科夫
You get it, Chekov?
是的 舰长 我追踪到了刚才通讯的位置
Aye, Captain, I have traced the location of her call.
克劳要这东西干什么
What does Krall want with this thing?
解救你们
To save you
别被自己消灭
from yourselves.
长官
Captain!
- 你没事吧 - 是的 舰长
- You all right? - Aye, Captain,
可我们被困住了
but we are trapped!
驱动器你能启动吗
Can you get this thing started?
你是说现在我们应该 发动推进器吗
Are you intimating that we should engage the thrusters?
那你还有其它办法吗
I am open to other suggestions.
好吧
Okay.
- 不过有个问题 先生 - 什么
- There is a problem. - What?
燃料倒是准备好了 可我没法让它燃烧起来
The fuel is primed, but I cannot get it to combust.
舰长 我们几乎就是站在一个非常大的炸弹上
Oy, Captain, we are basically standing on a very large bomb.
如果您没打到燃烧压缩机 舰长
If you miss the combustion compressor...
我不会的 行了
I'm not gonna miss, come on.
您知道燃烧压缩机长什么样吗
Do you even know what the combustion compressor looks like?
呃 是方的 对吗
It's square, right?
不对 舰长 是圆的
No, sir, it's round.
我刚才就那么说的
That's what I said.
跑
Run!
跳
Go!
契科夫
Chekov!
契科夫 跑
Chekov! Move!
你们以为自己知道
You think you know
牺牲的真正意义
what sacrifice really means?
星际联邦只会教你
Federation has taught you
冲突不应该存在
that conflict should not exist.
但是没有抗争
But without struggle,
你就永远不会了解真实的自己
you would never know who you truly are.
你根本不懂我们
You have no idea who we are.
但你很快就会明白
But you'll soon find out.
你说的是那个求救信号
You mean the distress signal
你们以为发送出去了
you thought you sent?
坐标被修改了
The coordinates were altered.
你们的救援飞船会被困在那片星云里
Your rescue ships will be stranded in the nebula
剩下你们的基地脆弱无防
and your base left vulnerable.
你要袭击约克城基地
You're going to attack Yorktown.
星际联邦所属的
Millions of souls
每一个世界 数百万人聚集在那里
from every Federation world holding hands.
一个完美的目标
It's a perfect target.
你错了 那是团结一致的力量
You're wrong. There is strength in unity.
这些其它人的力量 上尉
The strength of others, Lieutenant,
才让我继续生存下去
is what has kept me alive.
不
No!
斯波克
Spock.
斯波克 醒醒 见鬼
Spock, wake up, damn it!
我的意识很完整 医生
I am entirely conscious, Doctor.
我只是在沉思死亡的自然现象
I'm simply contemplating the nature of mortality.
感受哲学时的泰然自若 嗯
Feeling philosophical, huh?
我看你是大量失血才会这样的
Massive blood loss will do that to you.
你问过我乌胡拉上尉和我为何会分开
You asked me why Lieutenant Uhura and I parted ways.
是我有顾虑
I became concerned,
鉴于瓦肯星的消逝
in the light of Vulcan's demise,
我对自己的种族依然亏欠责任
that I owed a debt of duty to my species.
你觉得你应该去建设新瓦肯星 嗯
You thought you should be off making little Vulcans, huh?
是啊 能看出来这对她打击有多大
Yeah, I can see how that would upset her.
我本打算深入跟她讨论这件事
I intended to discuss it with her further,
但却收到一个对我产生了意外影响的消息
but I received some news which affected me unexpectedly.
什么消息
What news?
斯波克大使去世了
Ambassador Spock has died.
噢
Oh.
斯波克 真的很遗憾
Spock, I'm so sorry.
我可能没法想象 你现在的感受
I can't imagine what that must feel like.
像他那样经历过那么多的岁月
When you've lived as many lives as he,
畏惧死亡并不符合逻辑
fear of death is illogical.
畏惧死亡
Fear of death
才能继续生存下去
is what keeps us alive.
我想过他那样的一生
I want to live as he did.
所以我决定
That is why I decided
重新确定我努力的方向 继续他的工作
to redirect my efforts and continue his work
去新瓦肯星
on New Vulcan.
你要离开星际舰队
You're leaving Starfleet?
吉姆对这事儿怎么说
What did Jim have to say about that?
我还没找到时间 去告诉他
I could not find the time to tell him.
那我告诉你 他不会乐意的
Well, I can tell you he's not gonna like that.
见鬼 他要是没了你该怎么办
Hell, I don't know what he'd do without you.
我是说 要知道我已经安排了派对 不过
I mean, me on the other hand, I'd throw a party, but...
上帝 你这是犯糊涂了
My God, you're getting delirious.
离那个信号的坐标位置还有多远
How far are we from the coordinates of that call?
还很远呢 舰长
Still a ways, sir.
- 舰长 - 说吧
- Captain? - Yeah.
您是什么时候开始怀疑她的
When did you begin to suspect her?
还是不够早
Not soon enough.
您怎么发现的
How did you know?
我想说
Well...
你可以说我的好鼻子能嗅到危险
I guess you could say I've got a good nose for danger.
跑
Run!
那是音乐吗
Is that music?
到底从哪儿飘出来的
Where on earth is that coming from?
那里
There.
我把那个小盒子接到电源上
I plugged the little box in the power cell
然后那个小嘴唱歌了
and the little mouths make it sing.
真是非常聪明
That's very clever.
我对音乐的品味有点儿老派
Music's a bit old-fashioned for my taste,
更何况这些又吵 又会分心的音乐了
not to mention very loud and distracting,
不过也挺不错
but, aye, well played.
我喜欢有鼓点儿的节奏和喊叫
I like the beats and shouting.
是吗
Oh, you do?
- 关掉吧 - 没关系
- Switch it off. - Ach, you're okay.
快关掉
Switch it off!
有人踩到了我的陷阱
Someone set off one of my traps.
嘘
Shh.
是舰长
Captain?
- 你认识这两个人 - 是啊 小姑娘
- You know these men? - Aye, lassie.
- 那个小不点儿 就是帕维尔·契科夫 - 你好
- That wee man there is Pavel Chekov. - Hello.
那边帅气的混球 就是詹姆斯·T·柯克
And that handsome bastard is James T. Kirk.
都是我朋友
They're my mates.
看见你真高兴 长官
It's good to see you, sir.
她要干嘛 斯科蒂
What is she doing, Scotty?
请你不要伤害他们 因为如果你
Don't hurt them. No, don't!
这是什么鬼
Hit her!
你自由了 詹姆斯·T
You're free, James T.
起来吧
There we go.
斯科蒂先生
Mr. Scott.
这位新朋友是谁啊
Who's your new friend here?
还知道铺迎宾毯盛情款待
She sure knows how to throw out a welcome mat.
这位是婕拉
This is Jaylah.
我不知道什么事是迎宾毯
I do not know what is a welcome mat.
- 找到其他人了吗 - 没有 长官
- You find anybody else? - No, sir.
对不起 就只有你们俩
I'm sorry, you're the only ones.
进取号上到底出了什么事情 干嘛攻击我们
What the hell happened up there, Jim? Why were we attacked?
是为了我们从提纳克希带回来的那件武器
They were after the artifact we brought back from T eenax.
- 他们抢走了 - 没有
- Did they get it? - No.
- 那你拿走了 - 没有
- Have you got it? - No.
已经转移走了 放在了联络艇里
I had to get it off the Enterprise, put it on a shuttle.
- 把它藏在了联络艇 - 对
- You hid it in a shuttle. - Yes.
也不对
And no.
这是联邦星舰富兰克林号 长官 您能相信吗
This is the U. S. S. Franklin, sir. Can you believe it?
地球第一艘具备曲速4能力的星舰
First Earth ship capable of warp 4.
二十二世纪60年代早期在加加林辐射带失踪
Went missing in the Gagarin Radiation Belt in the early 2160s.
我记得在星舰学院听说过
I remember that from the Academy.
- 巴尔萨泽·爱迪生是舰长 - 是的
- Captain Balthazar Edison. - Aye.
舰队的早期英雄之一
One of the first heroes of Starfleet.
他的飞船怎么会落到这里
How the hell did his ship end up here?
说法就多了 长官
There's a lot of theories, sir.
比如向罗慕伦人投降
Surrendered to the Romulans.
被一只巨大的绿色太空手抓住
Captured by a giant green space hand.
落到这么远的地方 很有可能是被卷进了虫洞
This far out, it's got to be a wormhole displacement.
她还能飞吗
Can she fly?
她少了几个驱动器线圈
She's missing a few driver coils
少了几个电等离子系统导管
and the EPS conduits are fried,
不过婕拉做了了不起的工作
but Jaylah has done a marvelous job
让飞船的系统上线了
of getting the ship's systems back online.
谢谢 蒙哥马利·斯科蒂
Thank you, Montgomery Scotty.
噢 对不起
Pardon me.
契科夫先生 把坐标输进去
Mr. Chekov, can you plug in the coordinates.
看看飞船的传感器能否追踪到船员们的位置
See if you can track the crew's location from the ship's sensors.
是 舰长
Aye, Captain.
- 他喜欢那个座椅 - 斯科特先生
- He likes that seat. - Mr. Scott.
- 巡视一下 - 好的 去餐厅
- Tour. - Yes, the mess hall.
- 婕拉 你愿意的话 - 好的
- Jaylah, if you will. - Yes.
当时没有这些船员的消息吧
No clue what happened to the crew, huh?
没有 长官 到现在他们死了有一百年了
No, sir. They'd be dead a hundred years by now.
难道那是
Is that a...
这是PX-70
That's a PX70!
喔
Wow.
我爸小的时候就有一辆
My dad used to have one when he was a kid.
我妈说我爸把她放在后座上玩命地开
My mom said he'd put her on the back of it,
吓坏她了
drive her nuts.
长官
Sir.
呃
Um...
你是想告诉我它一直躺在这里
So you're telling me this thing's been here this whole time
从来没人动过
and no one's ever noticed it?
她装好了图像折射器
She's rigged up image refractors.
那儿 这儿
There. Here.
那 就像在用全息技术进行伪装
So, like some sort of holographic camouflage.
是的 长官
Aye, sir.
舰长
Captain!
我拦截到一个微弱的 通讯传输信号 舰长
I have intercepted a weak communications transmission, sir.
是星际舰队的频率
It's a Starfleet frequency.
传输检测
能锁定信号位置吗
Can you lock on to the signal?
能 可怎么去救他们呢
Yes, but how do we get to them?
我有个办法 长官
I have an idea, sir.
不过 一定得您准许
But I'm gonna need your permission.
为什么非得我准许
Why would you need my permission?
因为要是我搞砸了
Because if I mess it up,
我不想只是我一个人的错
I don't want it to be just my fault.
麦考伊 斯波克 呼叫进取号船员 回答
McCoy and Spock to Enterprise crew. Come in, Enterprise crew.
进取号船员
Anyone.
走吧 斯波克
Come on, Spock.
别泄气 你能行的
Come on, you can make it.
把我留下来
Leaving me behind
能显著增加你的生存机率 医生
will significantly increase your chances of survival, Doctor.
是 你倒还仗义
Well, that's damn chivalrous of you,
不过这事儿你想都别想
but completely out of the question.
你会找到其他生还的船员 这是必然的
It is imperative that you locate any surviving crew.
还以为你在乎的是我呢
And here I was thinking you cared.
我当然在乎你了
Of course I care, Leonard.
我始终认为 我对你的尊重很明确
I always assumed my respect for you was clear.
我们之间的谈话 这些年一直
The dialogue we have had across the years has always...
没关系 斯波克
It's okay, Spock.
用不着非说出来
You don't have to say it.
至少我不会孤独地死去
Well, at least I won't die alone.
此人真是堪称典范
Well, that's just typical.
都来啊 一群龟孙子
Come on, you bastards!
噢 天呐
Oh.
真高兴你没散架 医生
Good to see you in one piece, Doctor.
我吗
Oh, am I?
感觉内脏像在谷仓里跳舞
I feel like my innards have been to a barn dance!
是啊 这些老传送器原来只传送货物
Aye, well, these old transporters were only ever used for cargo,
不过 做些改装 似乎能传人了
but a few modifications seem to do the trick.
我想最好一次还是只传一个
I thought it best to beam you one at a time, though.
怕万一 你俩粘一块儿
You know, in case you got spliced.
我想不到还有更糟的情境了
I couldn't imagine a worse scenario.
很高兴你回来了 还好吧
Good to have you back. You all right?
是 我很好 他受伤了
Yeah, I'm fine. He's hurt.
我的身体机能可以胜任 舰长
I am functioning adequately, Captain.
睁眼说瞎话
In a pig's eye, you are!
舰长 我们发现我们得到的武器
Captain, we discovered that the stolen artifact
似乎来自于这颗行星
appears to have come from this planet.
真见鬼 斯波克
Damn it, Spock.
这地方连点医疗用品也没有吗
Are there any medical supplies on this thing?
在这边
This way.
好 躺下 来吧
All right. Lie down. Come on.
就这样躺好了
There you go.
我们这次该怎么办 斯波克
How are we gonna get out of this one, Spock?
我们 没有飞船 没有船员
We've got no ship, no crew.
几乎没有胜算
Not the best odds.
那就遵循我们一直做的 吉姆
We will do what we have always done, Jim.
在不可能之中找寻希望
We will find hope in the impossible.
好吧 先帮你包扎
Let's get you patched up first, okay?
不 舰长
No, Captain.
你必须把精力专注于帮助船员
You must focus your efforts on helping the crew.
所以我才需要你在我身边 斯波克
Well, that's why I need you around, Spock.
这些东西从黑暗时代来的
These things are from the dark ages.
老骨头
Bones.
我很肯定这是原生质修复器
I'm pretty sure this is a protoplaser.
应该能止住大量内出血的
Should stop the internal hemorrhaging.
至少我是这么希望
At least that's my hope.
解救苦难 并无其它良药 唯有希望
"The miserable have no other medicine But only hope."
都到死神门口了 他还引用莎士比亚
Death's door and he's quoting Shakespeare.
舰长日志 星历2263.18
Captain's Log, Stardate 2262.18.
任务是 进取号将例行调查
The mission, routine investigation...
我们找遍了飞船残骸，没有发现。一定藏在别处。
我们只抓住了他的船员，克劳。
如果宇宙真的无边无际
If the universe is truly endless...
对我来说 两年前看似清晰
What seemed so clear to me two years ago now seems,
现在 似乎又遥不可及
well, far away.
你会告诉我东西在哪儿
You will tell me where it is!
现在
Now!
住手 住手
Stop! Stop!
放过他 我就把你要的给你
Let him go and I will give you what you want!
不 希尔 不要
No! Syl, don't!
上尉 团结一致 不是你们的力量
Lieutenant, unity is not your strength.
它是 你们的弱点
It is your weakness.
应该等等 等到有绝对把握
We should wait until we're absolutely sure.
不行 必须现在就把船员救出来
No, we have to get the crew back now.
契科夫有准确的坐标
Chekov has the coordinates
能让我们找到他的老巢
that can lead us to Krall's base, so we go!
我们怎么知道卡拉莱联络他的时候
With respect, sir, how do we know that Krall was at the base
克劳是在老巢
when she called him?
就算他在那儿
Even if he was,
可我们也不知道船员在不在那儿
we don't know that the crew is even with him.
说不定他们都还活着
Or if they're even still alive.
契科夫先生 你可以重新设置搜索参数
Mr. Chekov, can you reconfigure the search parameters
来对这个公式进行补偿吗
in order to compensate for this formula?
是 中校 可是这是什么公式
Aye, Commander, but what is this formula?
这是瓦卡雅 契科夫先生
It is Vokaya, Mr. Chekov.
一种独特的瓦肯矿石
A mineral unique to Vulcan
可发射低能量级辐射
which emits low-level radiation.
那我就把其它所有能量辐射都过滤掉
I will have to filter out all other energy emissions.
斯波克 一块瓦肯矿石到底要怎么帮我们出去
Spock, what the hell would a Vulcan mineral be doing way out here?
告诉我们 这个是
Where are you going with this?
乌胡拉上尉戴着一个瓦卡雅护身符
Lieutenant Uhura wears a Vokaya amulet
是我赠与她的 象征感情和尊重
which I presented to her as a token of my affection and respect.
你送女朋友的珠宝有放射性
You gave your girlfriend radioactive jewelry?
辐射量对人无害 医生
The emission is harmless, Doctor.
但其独特的信号使之非常容易辨别
But its unique signature makes it very easy to identify.
你给女朋友送了一个跟踪装置
You gave your girlfriend a tracking device.
那并非我的本意
That was not my intention.
好吧 我很高兴他不尊重我
I'm glad he doesn't respect me.
我检测到了一个极其微弱的瓦卡雅信号
I am detecting a very trace amount of Vokaya.
是否与你从卡拉莱那里获得的坐标相匹配
Does the location match the coordinates you acquired from Kalara,
契科夫先生
Mr. Chekov?
匹配 长官
It is a match, sir.
信号的出现也就表示
Its presence suggests
乌胡拉上尉和其他的船员
that Lieutenant Uhura and thereby the rest of the crew
都被扣留在克劳的老巢内
are being held at Krall's base of operation.
能把他们传送出来吗
Can you beam them out?
不能 舰长 那里有某种地质上的干扰
No, sir. There is some geological interference
会阻挡传送器的信号
that is blocking the transporter signal.
那我们只能闯进去
Well, I guess we're gonna have to go in
用老办法把他们解救出来了
and break them out the old-fashioned way.
你们不能去这个地方
You cannot go to this place.
每一个去那里的人 他都杀
Everyone who goes there, he kills.
那 那你去过那里 你见过
You've... You've been there? You've seen it?
干嘛不说了 小姑娘
Well, why didn't you say something, lassie?
因为我知道你会要我带你去那里
Because I know you will ask me to take you there.
如果你的朋友在那里 他们会死
If your friends are there, then they will die,
像我家人一样
just like my family.
我绝对不回死亡的地方去
And I will not go back to that death place!
是 你是逃出来的
Aye, but if you've escaped,
那就能告诉我们进出的路
then you can show us the way in and the way out.
不 这不是我们的约定 蒙哥马利·斯科蒂
No! This is not the deal we made, Montgomery Scotty.
如果选择做这件事 那就靠自己
If you choose to do this, you are on your own.
噢 等等 等一下
Wait.
让她走吧
Let her go.
她也失去了她的族人 舰长
She's lost people, too, Captain.
在那儿的都是我们的朋友 对吗 小姑娘
Look, that's our friends out there, lassie. Right?
不能丢下他们不管
We cannae just leave them behind.
现在 我们真的需要你的帮助
Now, we could really use your help.
我们只希望你能勇敢一点儿
We just need you to be brave, is all.
我们还在那里的时候
When we were in that place,
克劳会来带走一个人
Krall would come and take someone.
那些叫声
There were screams.
到现在我还能听见
I can still hear them.
我们就再也看不到那个人了
And we would not see that person again.
我们也不知道谁是下一个
We did not know who would be next.
我父亲计划了一次逃跑
My father planned an escape.
但是被其中一个叫 玛纳斯的看到了
But we were seen by the one they call Manas.
我父亲跟他打了起来 所以我才能逃出来
My father fought him so I could get out.
他很勇敢 可玛纳斯杀了他
He was brave and Manas killed him.
你们想的事做不到
What you want is impossible.
也许不行 对吧
Look, maybe it's not.Right.
我祖母常说
My wee granny used to say,
一捆筷子你掰不断的
"Ya cannae break a stick in a bundle."
大事面前你是一分子 对吧
You're part of something bigger now, lassie.
可不能放弃
Right? Dinnae give up on that.
因为我们就绝对不会放弃你
'Cause we'll sure as hell never give up on you.
大家庭里一分子的意义就在这里
That is what being part of a crew is all about.
这就是你相信的吗 詹姆斯·T
Is that what you believe in, James T.?
我只知道 有你机会会更大
All I know is we stand a better chance with you.
挖掘的机器可以挖一个隧道 是通往坑地的
The digging machines uncovered a tunnel that goes into the crater.
我就是这么出来的
That's how I got out.
那我们就这么进去
So that'll be our way in.
外勤小队会被传送到隧道的另一边
An away team will beam to the other side of the tunnel,
往下走到克劳的老巢
follow it to Krall's base,
进入到建筑内部救人出来
get inside the building and break out the crew.
舰长 我们没有办法锁定坑地的任何人
Uh, Captain, we cannot lock onto anyone inside the crater
再把他传送出来
in order to beam them out.
可以装个脉冲信标 充当模式增强器
Oh, I could rig up pulse beacons as pattern enhancers.
- 让信号从坑地里传出来 - 是
That'd get the signal out of the crater. - All right.
富兰克林号一次能传送多少人
How many people can the Franklin transport at a time?
再做一点儿调校 20个最多
Uh, with a wee bit of modification, 20 max,
但我不清楚它能坚持多久
but I'm not sure how long it would hold out.
老骨头 契科夫 婕拉
Bones, Mr. Chekov, Jaylah,
跟我组成外勤小队
you're with me on the away team.
斯科特把传送器调校好
Mr. Scott, modify that transporter
- 然后尽一切可能让这艘星舰运转起来 - 是
- and then do everything you can to get this ship operational.- Aye.
舰长 契科夫对技术的敏锐
Captain, Mr. Chekov's technical acumen
使得他与斯科特留在这星舰上更有价值
makes him more valuable aboard the Franklin with Mr. Scott.
也因此由我替代他符合逻辑
It is thereby logical that I would replace him.
怎么就符合逻辑了 斯波克
Why is that logical, Spock?
你才刚好一点儿
You just got back on your feet.
乌胡拉上尉在那个设施里 吉姆
Lieutenant Uhura is in that facility, Jim.
我会把他看紧的
I'll keep an eye on him.
明白了
Understood.
可克劳的士兵到处都是
But his soldiers are everywhere.
进去会被看见
We won't pass unseen.
我们需要分散注意力的办法
What we require is a diversion.
我想我有个办法
I think I have an idea.
这就是艾布纳塞
This is Abronath.
它被古人们当做武器使用
It was used by the Ancient Ones as a weapon.
但不能控制它致命的威力
But when they could not control its deadly power,
于是 把它分成两半
they split it into two
投向了无尽的太空
and ejected the halves into space,
希望它永远消失
hoping it would be lost forever.
不过我很欣慰
But I am grateful.
我竭尽毕生 始终在寻找
I have spent lifetimes searching for it,
没料到你们替我
only to have you
找到了 另一半
find it for me.
一首命运的诗文
The poetry of fate.
我出生的那个世界
The world that I was born into
跟你们的截然不同
is very different from yours, Lieutenant.
我们经受过痛苦 体验过恐怖
We knew pain. We knew terror.
抗争让我们强大
Struggle made us strong.
没有和平 没有团结一致
Not peace. Not unity.
这些不过是联邦想让你们相信的谬论
These are myths the Federation would have you believe.
你说的那些言辞
Those are strong words.
也许你也相信这番话
You might even believe them,
可在你身上一定还有别的
but there's something else going on with you.
在你身体里面
Something underneath.
乌胡拉
Uhura!
等等
Wait.
你想把它怎么样
What are you doing with her?
你已经得到了你想要的东西 放她走
You already got what you wanted! Let her go!
希尔
Syl!
不要
No, please!
放她出来
Let her go!
玛纳斯 是时候了
Manas, it's time.
星际联邦将前沿疆域的推进
The Federation has pushed the frontier
持续了几个世纪
for centuries.
以后不会了
But no longer.
就从这里开始 上尉
This is where it begins, Lieutenant.
前沿疆域就从这里开始反击
This is where the frontier pushes back.
这边
This way.
她哪儿去了
Where is she?
我得承认这绝对分散注意力
I've got to admit, that's a hell of a distraction.
你们的朋友在那里
Your friends are over there.
走吧
Come on.
我去对付他们。
你带领我们走了很远。
完成我们的使命，克劳。
去吧
Go!
中校 乌胡拉被抓走了
Commander. Uhura, they took her.
带余下的船员去安全的地方
Get the remainder of the crew to safety.
快 我们走 快走
Come on, let's go! Move!
- 大家围成一圈 - 做好准备
- Stay in the circle. - Come on! Hurry!
我收到他们了 斯科特先生
I've got them, Mr. Scott!
好的 契科夫先生 增强信号强度
Okay, Mr. Chekov, increase the signal.
我们一次要传回20个人
We're gonna grab them 20 at a time.
- 是 - 希望这次别搞砸了
- Aye. - Let's hope this doesn't get messy.
传送
Energize!
斯波克
Spock.
你来这儿干什么
What are you doing here?
很明显 我是来救你的
Clearly, I am here to rescue you.
我们走
Let's go.
很高兴见到你 小不点儿
Good to see you, wee man.
你会死在这里…
就像你父亲一样。
传送器要10秒钟之后才能完成充能 医生
Ten seconds until the transporter's recharged, Doctor.
- 等我信号 - 医生
- Wait for my signal. - Doctor!
该死的 我们不能扔下他们
Damn it, man, we're not leaving without them!
快点儿 我们走
Come on. Let's go. Move!
快点儿 快走 快
Let's go! Come on!
准备好来接你们了 舰长 把你们的信标打开
We're ready for you next, Captain. Just turn on your beacon.
斯科蒂 人全接到了吗
Scotty, do you have everybody?
是的 长官 只剩你和婕拉
Aye, sir. Everyone except you and Jaylah.
打开信标 把你们传回来
Hit the beacon and we'll grab you.
你要被他们抛弃了。
舰长 打开信标
Captain, your beacon!
- 是信号 - 传送
- There it is! - Energize.
婕拉 快
Jaylah, now!
好了 好了
Okay...
下次可别这么玩了
Let's never do that again.
我同意 詹姆斯·T
I agree, James T.
你还好吗
You all right?
舰长 他手里的那东西 它
Captain! This thing he has...
约克城 他想摧毁约克城基地
Yorktown. He's gonna destroy Yorktown.
你用我的房子
You take my house
你要让它飞起来
and you make it fly.
斯科蒂 能让它发动起来吗
Scotty, can you get this thing started?
什么 发动可以 飞起来就另当别论了
Started, yes. Flying, sir, that's a different thing.
这种旧飞船直接在太空建造
These old vessels, they were built in space.
就没打算从大气层里起飞
They were never supposed to take off from atmosphere.
想办法让它飞
Make it happen.
叫它星际飞船是有道理的
They're called starships for a reason, Captain.
你现在跟我说这个
You're telling me this now?
因为我不想让你失望 对吧
Because I didn't want to disappoint you, you know,
万一你回不来呢
in case you didn't make it back.
你想得真周到 斯科特先生
How thoughtful, Mr. Scott.
舰长
Captain.
那家伙起飞了
He's launching.
攻击约克城基地可能只是个开始
The attack on Yorktown may be just the beginning.
装备这样的生物武器
Armed with this bio-weapon,
可以让他毁灭一切生命
he could rid it of all life
再利用基地的先进科技
and use the base's advanced technology
继而攻击隶属星际联邦的众多行星
to attack an untold number of Federation planets.
那我们就必须让这东西飞起来
Then we're just gonna have to get this thing flying.
不能跳线启动 长官
We cannae just jumpstart it, sir!
星际联邦 富兰克林号
星舰代码 NX-326
好嘞 所有系统上线
Okay! All systems online.
二锂室运行水平70% 还在上升
Dilithium chambers at 70% and climbing.
主动力引擎 准备就绪
Primary support engines standing by.
苏鲁先生
Mr. Sulu.
你能 就是 让它飞上天吧 嗯
You can, you know, fly this thing, right?
您开玩笑吧 长官
You kidding me, sir?
好极了
Fantastic.
斯科蒂 你那儿怎么样
Scotty, how we looking?
她永远都随时待命 长官
Ready as she'll ever be, sir.
我就爱听你这话 好了
That's what I like to hear. All right.
老骨头 船员们情况如何
Bones, where are we with the crew?
我还需要一个设施齐全的医疗舱
I could use a functioning med-bay,
其他的 我们在这儿很安全
but otherwise we're secure down here.
苏鲁先生
Mr. Sulu,
我们必须达到终端速度
we have to achieve terminal velocity
稳定器才能够提供足够的升力
in order for the stabilizers to provide lift.
您能肯定现在的 这个掉落高度够高吗
Are you sure this drop is high enough to do that?
会弄明白的
We'll find out.
开始吧 苏鲁先生
Call it, Mr. Sulu.
遵命 长官
Aye-aye, Captain.
契科夫先生 听我指令
Mr. Chekov,
准备完全打开前置稳定器
be ready to hit the forward stabilizers full on my mark.
- 四分之一脉冲速度 - 是
- One quarter impulse. - Aye.
二分之一脉冲速度 契科夫先生
One half impulse, Mr. Chekov.
是
Aye.
应该系安全带 快去 快快快 快去
We should belt up. Go on. Go!
慢着点儿 苏鲁先生 别把她摔成两半
Easy, Mr. Sulu. Let's not break her in half.
撞击距离
终端速度
随时点火 苏鲁先生
Any time, Mr. Sulu.
撞击距离
终端速度
就现在 契科夫先生
Now, Mr. Chekov!
敌我识别警告 有飞船接近
IFF alert on incoming vessel.
所有频率均未收到身份识别请求
No reply to all-frequency I.D. request.
显示
Visual.
多个不明身份飞船来袭
红色警戒 红色警戒
Red alert! Red alert!
看他们能有多先进
Look how far they've come.
所有人员
Please proceed
请立即前往指定的安全区
to designated safety zones immediately.
所有人员请立即前往指定的安全区
Please proceed to designated safety zones immediately.
我在所有来自约克城的频段上
I'm picking up distress signals
都监测到了求救信号
from every frequency coming from Yorktown.
克劳已经发动了攻击
Krall's already started his attack.
斯科特先生 我们手里有什么武器
Mr. Scott, what kind of weapons do we have?
我们有脉冲相位炮 还有空间鱼雷
Uh, we have pulsed phase cannons and spatial torpedoes.
很好 弹药上膛
Great. Lock and load.
这没有用处 你没有办法打败蜜蜂
It does not matter. You cannot defeat the bees.
好 也许 也许能把它们引开
Maybe, uh, maybe we lure them away.
我们怎么 怎么才能给约克城基地争取时间疏散呢
How do we get Yorktown time to get people to safety?
不行 跟那些东西比 我们就像马和马车
No, we are a horse and buggy compared to those things.
我们自己都快散架了 舰长
We're barely holding together as it is, Captain.
舰长
Captain,
蜜蜂的飞行模式由指定的个体决定
the flight patterns of bees are determined by individual decisions.
克劳的蜂群编队过于复杂
Krall's swarm formations are too complex not to rely
因此无法依赖某些形式的 统一神经网络感应协调
on some form of unified cyberpathic coordination.
- 根据我的推断 如果 - 斯波克
- I surmise that if we... - Spock!
直接说结论
Skip to the end.
他要说的是 如果我们能迷惑蜂群
What he's saying is that if we disorient the swarm
就能把他打垮
we can kick its ass!
很精确
Precisely.
斯科蒂 能把我传送到敌人的飞船上吗
Scotty, can you beam me onto one of those swarm ships?
你是不是已经彻底疯了
Have you gone completely mad?
- 能还是不能 - 不能
- Yes or no? - No!
能吧
Yes!
也许吧
Maybe.
舰长 我对那些飞船内部的熟悉程度
Captain, my familiarity of the interior of those ships,
简而言之 让我更具备外勤任务的资格
however brief, makes me more qualified for this away mission.
斯波克 你的伤还没好
Spock, you're still hurt.
她说得对 斯波克
She's right, Spock.
我对关切表示感谢
I acknowledge and respect your concerns.
或许你会感到更有信心 如果某位
Perhaps you would feel more confident if I were accompanied by someone
对飞船和我的伤情都很熟悉的人陪伴前往
with familiarity of both the ship and my injury.
他一定会喜欢的
He's gonna love this.
你想叫我干什么
You want me to do what?
请跟我来 医生
Come along, Doctor.
喔 等一下
Whoa! Wait a minute.
你这绿血怪 忘恩负义的
Why, you green-blooded ingrate.
是你的馊点子
This was your idea!
是个好点子 老骨头
It's a good idea, Bones.
你听好了 下回再有什么管子卡在你的腹部
You know, next time you have a piece of pipe
叫管道工帮你拔
stuck in your transverse, call a plumber.
务必想办法破坏那些飞船
Just make sure you find a way to break those things.
要是太危险 就马上传你们回来
If it gets hairy, I'll beam you straight back.
- 传送 - 等等 等
- Energize. - Wait...
圆满完成任务
You're gonna do great!
该死的 吉姆 我是医生 又不是
Damn it, Jim, I'm a doctor, not a...
你应该还记得上一次我开这玩意儿的时候
You do realize the last time I flew one of these things
是坠机了
we crashed.
所以你别怨我 要是
So don't blame me if we...
撞上了东西
Hit something.
斯波克呼叫富兰克林号
Spock to Franklin.
斯波克 我们听到了
Spock, we read you.
舰长 从探查情况来看
Captain, from what I can ascertain,
它们的确通过共享一个神经网络链接
the ships do indeed share a cyberpathic link
来协调行动
which coordinates their actions.
正在向你们转接
Patching it through now.
原来就是那个信号
That's what that signal was.
它们不是在干扰我们 而是在相互说话
They weren't jamming us, they were talking to each other.
怎么才能让它们说不了话呢
Well, how do we get them to stop talking?
那弄个电磁聚焦怎么样
What about electromagnetic focusing?
我们可以用传送器扰乱它们的网络
We could use the transporters, disrupt their network.
有焦点或许过于明确
The focus might be too specific.
如果我们可以把某种扰乱通讯的信号
If we could plant some sort of disruptive communication signal
植入蜂群内部
inside the swarm,
或许会对它们的协同能力产生不利影响
it might adversely affect their capacity to coordinate.
一定要设在一个它们想象不到的频率上
It would have to be at a frequency they will not anticipate.
然后我们再引发连锁反应
We could cause a chain reaction
就能击垮整个蜂群
that would wipe out the whole swarm.
长官 像那样的封闭式网络
Sir, a closed network like that
可能会受到甚高频的影响
might be susceptible to very high frequency.
甚高频
VHF.
无线电
Radio.
我们 我们可以从飞船上广播什么东西
We can broadcast something from the ship
扰乱它们的网络
to drown out their link.
又吵又会分心的
Something loud and distracting.
Loud and distracting?
我这儿正好就有
I've got just the thing!
不要弄坏我的音乐
Do not break my music.
弄坏 这是要给你升级
Break it? You're getting an upgrade.
再过60秒蜂群飞船就要攻入基地了
Swarm ships are 60 seconds from breaking through!
我只要重新配置甚高频输出
I've just got to reconfigure the VHF output
给它接上一个多相扫描器
into a multiphasic sweep.
让我来接
Let me do it.
让她接
Let her do it.
还是该让你接
You do it.
这样 看 很简单
There, see? Simple.
好了 舰长 我们准备好广播了
All right. Captain, we're ready to broadcast.
但信号没法传递太远 我们得近点儿
But the signal won't travel far. We have to get closer.
- 要多近 - 很近
- How close? - Very.
拦截航线 苏鲁先生
Intercept course, Mr. Sulu.
让我们直接飞到它们中间去
Put us right in the middle of that thing.
是 先生
Yes, sir.
我的老朋友
My old friend.
约克城星舰基地
蜂群转向回来了
The swarm ships are doubling back!
它们正在集结成一波攻势 舰长
They are forming an attack wave, sir.
已经吸引到它们的注意了
I think we got their attention.
把稳舵 苏鲁先生
Hold steady, Mr. Sulu.
所有人都打起精神来
Brace yourselves, everybody.
斯波克 准备待命退出蜂群
Spock, stand by to drop out of formation.
斯科蒂 都准备妥当了吗
Scotty, you all cued up back there?
是 长官
Aye, sir!
准备进行广播 频率57.7兆赫
Ready to broadcast at 577 megahertz.
选好哪首了 小姑娘
Made your choice, lassie?
我要带鼓点儿和喊叫的
I have the beat and shouting.
我们来点儿噪音
Let's make some noise.
这个选得不错啊
That's a good choice.
再快点儿 医生
Faster, Doctor.
它们的轨迹衰变 我们会有爆燃的风险
We risk being consumed by their trajectorial decay.
指手画脚的后座司机
Damn backseat driver.
闪避 医生
Evade, Doctor!
没错 我看见 看见了
I see it, I see it!
这算是古典音乐
Is that classical music?
是的 医生 似乎是这样
Yes, Doctor, it would seem to be.
乌胡拉上尉
Lieutenant Uhura,
让约克城基地也用相同频率进行广播
make sure Yorktown has the frequency to broadcast.
长官 我们收到了干扰频率
Sir, we now have the disruption frequency.
广播
Broadcast.
你们俩没事吧 斯波克
You two all right, Spock?
我们没事 舰长
We are fine, Captain,
但仍有三艘飞船飞向约克城基地
but there are still three ships heading into Yorktown.
一定是克劳 跟着他 斯波克
That's got to be Krall. Keep on him, Spock.
要不惜一切代价 绝不能让他用那种武器
Do whatever it takes to stop him from using that weapon.
我的房子要坏了
My house is breaking!
我们失去了舰体装甲极性
We've lost the polarization of the hull plating!
我得把二锂室的动力重新布线
I can reroute the power from the dilithium chambers.
我需要你
I need you.
还有你 婕拉 我们走
And I need you, Jaylah. Let's go!
不能跟丢 医生
Do not lose them, Doctor.
我很欢迎你来跟我换个位置 斯波克
You're more than welcome to switch places with me, Spock.
舰长 拦截三艘飞船是不可能的
Captain, intercepting all three ships is an impossibility.
给我约克城基地的结构图
Get me a schematic of Yorktown!
那儿 约克城基地总部
There! Yorktown headquarters!
契科夫先生 能对中央广场做一次生物扫描吗
Mr. Chekov, can you do a bioscan of Central Plaza?
是
Aye.
他们正在疏散平民
They are clearing civilians.
老骨头 前面有个城市广场
Bones, there's a city plaza coming up.
你必须把克劳的飞船赶到那里
You gotta make sure Krall heads for it.
- 为什么 - 你就照做
- Why? - Just do it!
苏鲁 让我们拉起来
Sulu, get us up there.
大家抓紧了
Hold onto something!
干得漂亮 老骨头
Great work, Bones.
谢了 吉姆
Thanks, Jim.
眼下我得弄明白怎么降落
Now I've just got to figure out how to land.
舰长 撞击导致了三处舰体破裂
Captain, I have three hull breaches from the impact.
第三层甲板 货舱 还有轮机室
Deck 3, the cargo bay, and the engine room.
- 好了 苏鲁 契科夫 - 是
- All right, Sulu, Chekov. - Aye.
去检查一下货舱和第三层甲板
check the cargo bay and Deck 3.
必须证实那个武器已经被销毁
We need confirmation that the weapon has been neutralized
克劳也已经死亡
and Krall is dead!
舰长
Captain!
是克劳
It's Krall.
我们见他干过
We've seen him do this.
这应该是某种能量转移 能改变他的身体
It's some kind of energy transference. It physically changes him.
他一定还在星舰上 否则应该看到他离开
He must still be onboard. We would have seen him leave.
苏鲁 联络约克城基地的安全部门
Sulu, contact Yorktown security
封锁这艘飞船
and lock down the ship.
我们走
Let's go.
向前沿疆域推进
Push the frontier.
时间差不多了
It's about damn time.
- 好了吗 长官 - 是的
- Are you ready? - Yeah.
好了 宝贝儿 我们走
All right, baby, let's go.
- 时间差不多了 - 向前沿疆域推进
- It's about damn time. - Push the frontier.
舰长
Captain!
- 时间差不多了 - 向前沿疆域推进
- It's about damn time. - Push the frontier.
向前沿疆域推进
...frontier.
就是他
It's him.
斯科蒂 我要你链接富兰克林号的数据库
Scotty, I need you to link into the Franklin database.
想办法弄清楚巴尔萨泽·爱迪生的情况
Find out what you can about Balthazar Edison.
- 什么 富兰克林号舰长 - 没错
- The captai n of the Franklin? - Yeah.
- 长官 他已经死很久了 - 不 他没有
- Sir, he'll be long dead. - No. He's not.
不清楚是怎么回事 但爱迪生就是克劳
I don't know how, but Edison is Krall.
你有什么发现
What'd you find?
呃 那个 他的记录
His record goes back
可以追溯到星际联邦成立之前
way before the Federation even existed.
巴尔萨泽·爱迪生
.
他是地球武装突击小队的一名少校
He was a major in the United Earth Military Assault
执行过大量地球以外的任务
Command Operation. A lot of off-world combat.
他是个军人
He was a soldier.
是 而且非常优秀
Aye, sir. And a pretty good one.
但是小队遣散后他的生涯就结束了
His military service came to an end when MACO was disbanded.
为什么了 怎么了
Why, what happened?
是联邦 长官
The Federation, sir.
星际舰队不是军事机构
Starfleet. We're not a military agency.
他们让他当了舰长 给了他富兰克林号
They made him a captain and gave him the Franklin.
- 把他的日志调出来 - 是 长官
- Scotty, bring up his logs. - Aye, sir.
舰长日志
Captain's Log...
最后一条
Last entry.
舰长日志 已经记不起星历是哪一天了
Captain's Log... I don't remember the stardate.
所有的求救呼叫都没有回应
All distress calls unanswered.
至于船员
Of the crew,
也只剩下了三个
only three remain.
我绝不允许
I won't allow it!
这里的原生物种很早以前就遗弃了这颗行星
The indigenous race abandoned this planet long ago.
他们留下了非常精密复杂的采矿设备
They left behind sophisticated mining equipment
和能充当劳力的无人机
and a drone workforce.
他们有某种技术
They have some sort of technology
能够延长人的 寿命
that prolongs life.
不管要我和我的船员付出什么代价 我都愿意
I will do whatever it takes for me and my crew.
星际联邦根本不在乎我们
The Federation do not care about us.
你们可能再也见不到我了
You'll probably never see me again.
万一见到了
But if you do,
做好准备
be ready.
为什么他还没有用他的武器
Why has he not used his weapon yet?
因为他要找能造成最大破坏力的地方
'Cause he wants to find somewhere to inflict maximum damage.
他需要一个能流通的系统
He needs a distribution system.
是这里的空气循环系统
They have to circulate air here, right?
是的 长官 基地核心有一个大气空气调节器
Aye, sir. There's an atmospheric regulator at the core.
上尉 联络基地
Lieutenant, contact Yorktown.
- 在找到克劳之前 务必关闭调节器 - 明白
- Make sure they shut it down until we find Krall. - Yes.
怎么样才能进入核心区域
How would he access the core?
呃 这个
Uh, well,
在空间站的重力结合点有一座维修塔
there's a maintenance tower at the station's gravitational nexus.
只有一条路
That's the only way.
斯科蒂 你去基地控制室 一定要保证关闭它
Scotty, you get over there. Make sure it gets shut down!
小姑娘 跟我走
Lassie, you're with me.
这个东西 你没有办法把它关掉
Look, this thing is impossible to shut down.
是吗 好吧
Aye, well,
那我试试看
we'll see about that.
斯科蒂先生 调节器怎么还没关掉
Mr. Scott, why is that thing still on?
我们正在努力 长官
We're working on it, sir,
但你该明白我要突破很多安全协议
but as you can imagine there's a lot of safety protocols
毕竟这玩意儿关系到
surrounding the thing that, you know,
- 所有人的性命 - 想想办法
- keeps everybody alive. - Figure something out.
小心点儿 舰长
Be careful, Captain.
你越靠近核心
Gravity's gonna get a bit screwy
重力的作用就越混乱
the closer you get to the center.
也许 我们该扫描一下结构图
Maybe we should scan the operational schematics,
- 看有没有后门 - 好的
- see if there's a back door. - Right.
小姑娘 我需要你帮忙
Lassie, I'm gonna need your eyes.
住手
Stop!
你在那个星球经历了什么事情
What happened to you out there, Edison?
爱迪生
Edison.
我不得不说 柯克
I have to say, Kirk,
我怀念过去的自己
I've missed being me.
我们失去了自我
We lost ourselves
但找到了目标
but gained a purpose!
我们要让银河系重新陷入争斗
A means to bring the galaxy back to the struggle
让人类变得强大
that made humanity strong.
我觉得你低估了人类
I think you underestimate humanity.
我曾经为人类而战
I fought for humanity!
同新地人和罗慕伦人的战争中 我们牺牲数以百万
Lost millions to the Xindi and Romulan Wars.
这一切为了什么
And for what?
为了一个星际联邦的舰长职位
For the Federation to sit me in a captain's chair
为了跟敌人握手言和
and break bread with the enemy.
时代变了 我们必须与时俱进
We change. We have to.
否则我们就会陷入永无休止的战争
Or we spend the rest of our lives fighting the same battles.
你已经输了
You lost!
你不可能过得去的
There's no way you can make it back there.
放弃吧
Give up.
像你一样吗
What, like you did?
我看过你的舰长日志
I read your ship's log,
詹姆斯·T·柯克舰长
Captain James T. Kirk.
至少我知道我是谁
At least I know what I am.
我是一个军人
I am a soldier.
你打赢了战争 爱迪生
You won the war, Edison.
你为我们创造了和平
You gave us peace.
和平
Peace
我出生的时代没有和平
is not what I was born into.
斯科蒂
Scotty.
舰长 他正在试图利用重力涡流返回核心
Captain, he's using the gravitational slipstream to carry him back to the center.
不 不
No! No!
- 那是什么 - 是那武器
- What's that? - The weapon's in the chamber.
检测到外来元素
- 那是什么 - 是那武器
- What's that? - The weapon's in the chamber.
检测到外来元素
舰长 我们必须马上阻止他
Captain, we have to stop the processor now
不然约克城里所有要喘气的生物都完了
or everything breathing in Yorktown is dead!
你休想阻止
You can't stop it.
你死定了
You will die.
为拯救他人牺牲自己
Better to die saving lives
好过牺牲他人拯救自己
than to live with taking them.
这就是我出生的时代
That's what I was born into.
斯科蒂
Scotty!
长官 我想我能重新引导气流方向
Captain, I think we can redirect it.
那里有一个排气舱口
There's a sealed construction hatch
打开阀门就能把武器排放到太空
that will let you vent the weapon into space.
我可以在这边远程解锁
Now, we can override the locks from up here,
但还需要你进行手动操作
but you will have to activate the hatch.
我只要按一下按钮吗
So I just hit a button.
那不是按钮 长官
It's not a button, sir.
是白色面板下面的银色拉杆
It's a silver lever under a white panel.
- 看到了 - 一共四个
- Got it! - And there's four of them.
一旦打开排气舱口
Once you've primed the hatch,
你必须马上离开
you'll have to exit the chamber immediately.
系统开始循环后 舱口就会打开
If the hatch is open when the processor cycles
如果你还在里面 就会被吸入到太空
and you're in it, you're gonna get sucked into space.
要是我打不开舱口呢
What happens if the hatch isn't open?
你会被吸进大风扇里
You're gonna get sucked into a big fan.
包括那武器 我们都会完蛋
With the weapon, and we all die.
该死 吉姆 你恐怕来不及了
Damn it, Jim, you won't make it out in time!
排气舱口
The vent!
快离开 詹姆斯·T
Get out of there, James T.!
斯科蒂 最后一个舱口打不开
Scotty, the last hatch won't open!
斯科蒂
Scotty!
排气系统开启倒计时
快啊 舰长 没时间了
Work fast, Captain, time's running out!
排气系统开启倒计时
恐怕他搞不定了
He's not gonna make it.
不 不
No! No!
进入手动操作模式
Manual override engaged.
没有你我该怎么办 斯波克
What would I do without you, Spock?
巴尔萨泽·爱迪生
关闭档案
.
多年来 星际联邦一直宣传他是个英雄
For decades the Federation taught that he was a hero.
我想时间才能评判一切
I guess time will judge us all.
他只是迷失了自我
He just got lost.
你拯救了整个基地 柯克
You saved this entire base, Kirk.
拯救了数百万人 谢谢你
Millions of souls. Thank you.
这不是我的功劳 从来不是
It wasn't just me. It never is.
毋庸赘言 中将这个职位是你的了
Needless to say, the position of Vice Admiral is yours.
没人比你更适合
No one deserves it more.
中将不需要随舰出航吗
Vice Admirals don't fly, do they?
是的 不需要
No. They don't.
恕我冒犯 长官
Well, no offense, ma'am,
那还有什么乐趣可言
but where's the fun in that?
斯波克大使私人物品
你没争取申请缩短任务时间吗
You didn't even try to get our time out here reduced?
为什么要缩短任务时间
Why would I get it reduced?
老骨头 我们现在知道穿过星云的航线了
Bones, we know our way through the nebula now.
想想看 我们会发现什么
Can you imagine what we'll find!
妄想消灭人类的外星暴君
Alien despots hell-bent on killing us?
致命的外星病毒 微生物
Deadly space-borne viruses and bacteria?
还有能瞬间消灭我们的宇宙异形
Incomprehensible cosmic anomalies that could wipe us out in an instant!
那该多有意思啊
It's gonna be so much fun.
顺便问问 我们去哪儿
By the way, where are we going?
不是去喝一杯吗
I thought we were gonna get a drink.
我知道你说要保密 但是
I know you told me to keep it under wraps, but, uh...
生日快乐
Happy Birthday!
敏感先生
Mr. Sensitive?
- 给你 拿好 - 谢了 斯科蒂
- There you go, laddie. - Thanks, Scotty.
各位 举起酒杯
Everybody, raise a glass
敬舰长詹姆斯·T·柯克
to Captain James T. Kirk.
- 柯克舰长 - 谢谢大家
- Captain Kirk! - Thanks, everybody.
- 敬进取号 - 敬进取号
- To the Enterprise. - To the Enterprise.
还有
And
逝去的朋友
to absent friends.
- 敬逝去的朋友 - 干杯
- Here's to that. - Cheers.
好了 派对开始了
All right, let's get this party started.
轮到谁了
Whose round is it?
给我来三杯 罗慕伦麦芽酒
Can I get three, uh, Romulan ales for me?
我以为你要完成任务报告
I thought you had to finish your mission report.
原本是的
I do.
但我评估和你参加社交活动会更加愉悦
But I thought it would be more pleasing to engage with you socially.
你的套路太老了
You old romantic.
你知道吗
Do you know that
苏格兰威士忌其实是一位俄国老太太发明的
scotch was actually invented by a little old lady in Russia?
- 呃 很少人知道 - 失陪一下
- Huh? Not many people know. - Excuse me.
你一个人喝这么多 真厉害
Uh, did you drink all those yourself? I'm impressed.
有人告诉我 喝这个能放松心情
Someone said it will take my edge off.
我还是不能放松
My edge is still not off.
好吧 也许这个可以帮你
All right, well, maybe this will help.
舰长找了点儿关系
Captain pulled a few strings.
这是星舰学院的入学证书 只要你愿意
That is acceptance into Starfleet Academy, if you want it.
那里的条条框框很多 不必太当真
They have a lot of rules. Don't listen to them all.
我必须穿那个制服吗
Will I have to wear that uniform?
恐怕是的
Afraid so.
你好 金瑟
Hey, Keenser.
凯文 你还是不穿裤子吗
Kevin. Still not wearing pants, I see.
我听说了斯波克大使的事
I heard about Ambassador Spock.
上次在电梯里 你想说的就是这事吧
Is that what you wanted to mention that time in the turbolift?
很接近
More or less.
我想你和帕里斯指挥官的会面应该很顺利
I trust your meeting with Commodore Paris went well.
很接近
More or less.
你真的很想重返太空 嗯
You really want to head back out there, huh?
太空
Space,
最后的疆域
the final frontier.
这是进取号星舰的旅程
These are the voyages of the Starship...
她的使命 是探索陌生的新世界
...Enterprise. Its continuing mission...
寻找新的生命
To explore strange new worlds.
和新的文明
To seek out new life.
勇敢地去探索
And new civilizations.
前人从未踏足过的地方
To boldly go where no one has gone before.